treehouse-app.com 2014-12-30

# Treehouse | Privacy Policy

We at Treehouse Island, Inc. (“Treehouse,” “Company,” “we,” “us,” “our”) know that our users (“you,” “your”) care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. By visiting or using the teamtreehouse.com site and our mobile applications (the “Website”) or any related services offered by the Company (the “Services”) in any manner, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways. Any capitalized terms used herein without definition shall have the meaning given to them in the Treehouse Terms and Conditions which can be found at <http://teamtreehouse.com/terms>.

Treehouse Island, Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy and Children's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Website [teamtreehouse.com](http://teamtreehouse.com/) and Treehouse mobile app.

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [help@teamtreehouse.com](mailto:help@teamtreehouse.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

Treehouse Island, Inc. complies with the U.S.–E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S.–Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Treehouse Island, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Treehouse Island, Inc.’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

* ### WHAT DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVER?

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) and other information that we gather when you or your child are accessing or using our Website. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, or to individuals that we do not employ or manage.

* ### WHAT INFORMATION DOES COMPANY COLLECT?

We gather various types of Personal Information from our users, as explained more fully below. We may use this Personal Information to personalize and improve our services, to allow our users to set up a user account and profile, to contact users, to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, to analyze how users utilize the Website, and as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. We may share certain types of Personal Information with third parties (described in this Section and in Section 3 below). We collect the following types of information:

A. Information You Provide to Us:

We receive and store any information you knowingly provide to us. For example, we collect Personal Information such as your name, email address, parent's email address, child's name, child's email address, physical address, browser information, birth date, zip code, unique identifiers related to different workforce investment boards (for example a Job Seeker ID), location, and details of transactions including a credit card number, that you carry out through the Website. If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence. If you contact us and you are under 13, we will only retain this information if a parent has given us consent to do so. At anytime parents may request deletion of such information by contacting us at help@teamtreehouse.com. You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to register with us or to take advantage of some of our features. We may anonymize your Personal Information so that you cannot be individually identified, and provide that information to our partners.

Anytime you post on our blog please be aware that you are posting using a third party application and we have no access or control over this information. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, you can either log into the third party application and remove your comment or you can contact the appropriate third party application. Your interaction with these features is governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [help@teamtreehouse.com](mailto:help@teamtreehouse.com).

B. Information Collected Automatically:

  1. Whenever you interact with our Website, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, “cookie” information, and the page you requested. “Cookies” are identifiers we transfer to your computer or mobile device that allow us to recognize your browser or mobile device and tell us how and when pages in our Website are visited and by how many people. You may be able to change the preferences on your browser or mobile device to prevent or limit your computer or device’s acceptance of cookies, but this may prevent you from taking advantage of some of our Website’s features. Also, if you click on a link to a third party website, such third party, for example marketing partners or analytics service providers, may also transmit cookies to you. This Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties. These cookies are used to analyze trends and remarket/retarget advertisements to non-converted visitors. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.
  2. We employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.
  3. Our Website includes social media features, such as the Facebook button and widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Gravatar or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like these give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.
  4. When we collect usage information (such as the numbers and frequency of visitors to the Website, the length of stay on the Website, the types of pages visited and other general information), we only use this data in aggregate form, and not in a manner that would identify you personally. For example, this aggregate data tells us how often users use parts of the Website, so that we can make the Website appealing to as many users as possible. We may also provide this aggregate information to our partners; our partners may use such information to understand how often and in what ways people use our Website, so that they, too, can provide you with an optimal experience. We never disclose aggregate information to a partner in a manner that would identify you personally.
  5. When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operations system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID"). We do not ask for, access or track any location based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Apps or Services.

C. E-mail and Other Communications:

We may contact you, by email or other means; for example, we may send you promotional offers on behalf of other businesses, or communicate with you about your use of the Website. If you do not want to receive email or other mail from us, please indicate your preference on the account notifications page at <http://teamtreehouse.com/account/notifications>. Please note that if you do not want to receive legal notices from us, those legal notices will still govern your use of the Website, and you are responsible for reviewing such legal notices for changes. We may use your child's personal information to retarget ads to you or your child on other sites. To opt out of this type of retargeting, please contact us at [help@teamtreehouse.com](mailto:help@teamtreehouse.com). We will not retarget ads to your child without your prior consent to do so.

* ### WILL COMPANY SHARE ANY OF THE PERSONAL INFORMATION IT RECEIVES?

We neither rent nor sell your Personal Information in personally identifiable form to anyone. We share your Personal Information in personally identifiable form with third parties as described below. Parents have the right to consent to our collection and use of Personal Information collected from their child, without having to also consent for its disclosure to third parties as we do not share this type of personal information with third parties.

A. Affiliated Businesses and Third Party Websites We Do Not Control: In certain situations, businesses or third party websites we’re affiliated with may sell items or provide services to you through the Website (either alone or jointly with us). You can recognize when an affiliated business is associated with such a transaction or service, and we will share your Personal Information with that affiliated business only to the extent that it is related to such transaction or service. Treehouse works with workforce investment boards or other government agencies to provide job training. If you are participating in one of those programs (for example our Code USA initiatives), we may share some of your personally identifiable information and learning activity with our partners and their affiliated workforce retraining centers. This is a requirement from our partners.

B. Agents: We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf, such as our payment processor or hosting provider, and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you. Unless we tell you differently, our agents do not have any right to use the Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us.

C. Business Transfers: We may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Also, if we (or substantially all of our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, Personal Information would be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

D. Protection of Company and Others: We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we reasonably believe is necessary to comply with law or court order; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Company, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

E. With Your Consent: Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be able to prevent the sharing of this information.

* ### IS PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT ME SECURE?

Your account is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You must prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer or device and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. When you enter sensitive information, such as a credit card number, on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We endeavor to protect the privacy of your account and other Personal Information we hold in our records, but we cannot guarantee complete security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time. Transmission of information via the Internet can never be completely secure, and all such transmission is at your risk.

The Website may contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When following a link to another site you should read that site’s privacy policy.

* ### WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION CAN I ACCESS?

Through your account settings, you may access, and, in some cases, edit or delete the following information you have provided to us:

  * name and password;
  * child's name and password;
  * child's email address;
  * email address;
  * location; and
  * user preferences.

The information you can view, update, and delete may change as the Website changes. If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at [help@teamtreehouse.com](mailto:help@teamtreehouse.com). We will respond to your request to access personal information on file with us within 30 days.

Parents have the right to review personal information collected from their child, have that personal information deleted or refuse further collection and use of personal information by logging into their child's account and selecting account settings or by emailing us at the email address listed above. 

* ### WHAT CHOICES DO I HAVE?

You can always opt not to disclose information to us, but keep in mind some information may be needed to register with us or to take advantage of some of our special features.

You may be able to add, update, or delete information as explained in Section 5 above. When you update information, however, we may maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. You may request deletion of your account by contacting us at help@teamtreehouse.com. Please note that some information may remain in our private records after your deletion of such information from your account. We will retain yours or your child's information for as long as yours or your child's account is active or as needed to provide services. We will also retain and use yours or your child's information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may use any aggregated data derived from or incorporating yours or your child's Personal Information after you update or delete it, but not in a manner that would identify you personally.

You may request details of any of yours or your child's Personal Information held by us, and where necessary, have it corrected. Such requests may be subject to a fee of $15 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the personal data we hold about you. For more details, please contact us at [help@teamtreehouse.com](mailto:help@teamtreehouse.com).

* ### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make material changes in the way we use Personal Information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on our Website or sending you an email prior to the change becoming effective. You are bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when you use the Website after such changes have been first posted.

If we make material changes to how we use Personal Information collected from children under age 13, we will notify parents by email in order to obtain verifiable parental consent for the new uses of the child's Personal Information.

* ### QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy policies, please send us a detailed message to help@teamtreehouse.com or to our address below. We will make every effort to resolve your concerns.

Treehouse Island Inc.  
622 E Washington Street  
Suite 240  
Orlando FL 32801, USA

1 (800) 928 2130

Effective Date: Sep 25, 2014
